[
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "An Act establishing the national service training program (NSTP) for tertiary level students?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "RA 9163"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "An act providing for the development, administration, organization, training, maintenance and utilization of the Citizen Armed Forces of the Philippines.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Reservist Act of 1991"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "To train students to teach literacy and numeracy skills to school children, out-of-school youth and other segments in society.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "LTS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "To train students to extend services in the community in the area of health, education, environment, safety, recreation and other social welfare services.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "CWTS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "For the Cadets to be indoctrinated and equipped with the basic knowledge on fundamentals and principles of military training in tertiary level.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "ROTC"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Also known as the citizen armed forces of the Philippines.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "RA 7077"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Its mission is to provide base of expansion of the AFP and perform active military, civic and auxiliary services in the areas of maintaining law, operations, peace and order and socio-economic development.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Reserve Force"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Literacy Training Service stands for?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "LTS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Reserve officer Training Corps stands for?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "ROTC"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Civic Welfare Training Service stands for?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "CWTS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "The following are the components of NSTP except?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["ROTC", "LTS", "CWTS", "AIR FORCE"],
    "answer": "AIR FORCE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "For the Cadets to be indoctrinated and equipped with the basic knowledge on fundamentals and principles of military training in tertiary level.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["ROTC", "LTS", "CWTS", "Navy"],
    "answer": "ROTC"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "To train students to extend services in the community in the area of health, education, environment, safety, recreation and other social welfare services.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["ROTC", "LTS", "CWTS", "AFP"],
    "answer": "CWTS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "To train students to teach literacy and numeracy skills to school children, out-of-school youth and other segments in society.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["ROTC", "LTS", "CWTS", "AFP"],
    "answer": "LTS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "The following are the categorization of the reserve Force except in one",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Ready Reserve", "Retired Reserve", "Standby Reserve", "For Reserve"],
    "answer": "For Reserve"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Aimed at enhancing civic consciousness and defense preparedness in the youth by developing the ethics of service and patriotism by undergoing.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["ROTC", "LTS", "CWTS", "NSTP"],
    "answer": "NSTP"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "It is an Act establishing the national service training program (NSTP) for tertiary level students?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["RA 7077", "RA 4962", "RA 9163", "RA 1991"],
    "answer": "RA 9163"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "It is an act providing for the development, administration, organization, training, maintenance and utilization of the Citizen Armed Forces of the Philippines.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["RA 7077", "RA 4962", "RA 9163", "RA 1991"],
    "answer": "RA 1991"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "The Ranks of Members of the Reserve Force maybe upgraded if they voluntarily participate in the training or serve with the ready Reserve units.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["RA 7077", "Art V. Section 13-14 R.A 7077", "RA 9163", "RA 1991"],
    "answer": "Art V. Section 13-14 R.A 7077"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Its mission is to provide base of expansion of the AFP and perform active military, civic and auxiliary services.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["AFP", "NAVY", "Reserve Command", "Reserve Force"],
    "answer": "Reserve Force"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "ROTC is one of the Components of NSTP?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "26 Hours must spend off camp or activities outside the camp or training sites are on of the Regulations of NSTP Law.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "There are three (3) Categorization in the Reserve Force.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Art V. Section 13-14 R.A 7077 States: The Ranks of Members of the Reserve Force maybe upgraded if they voluntarily participate in the training or serve with the ready Reserve units.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "NSTP, CWTS, LTS, and ROTC are the components of NSTP",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "ROTC to train students to teach literacy and numeracy skills to school children, out-of-school youth and other segments in society.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "LTS is to train students to extend services in the community in the area of health, education, environment, safety, recreation and other social welfare services.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "CWTS are for Cadets to be indoctrinated and equipped with the basic knowledge on fundamentals and principles of military training in tertiary level.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "Army, Air Force, Navy Reserve Components, the AFP-Wide Technical Reserve and the Affiliated Reserves are the component of RA 7077",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 1,
    "question": "NSTP Aimed at enhancing civic consciousness and defense preparedness in the youth by developing the ethics of service and patriotism by undergoing.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Uphold the sovereignty, support the Constitution and defend the territory of the country this is?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Function"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "What is the vision of the Philippine army?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Serving the people securing the Land"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Consists of all standing forces and such number of reserve officers and reservist units.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Regular"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Through him, the President issues orders to all AFP Commanders.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Chief of Staff of AFP"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "To defend the Republic of the Philippines, safeguards its national security, and to assist government agencies in the socio-economic development of the country.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Mission"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "This is one of AFP Major Services that protect and sustained in the sea?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Navy"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "This is one of AFP Major Services that protect and sustained in the land",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Army"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "What is the AFP Major Services?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Navy, Army, Air Force"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Who is the Secretary of national Defense?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Sec, Delfin N Lorenzana"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "A mission to organize, train, and equip army forces for the conduct of prompt and sustained land combat?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["AFP", "PA", "PN", "PAF"],
    "answer": "PA"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "A mission to organize, train, and equip the air combat?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["AFP", "PA", "PN", "PAF"],
    "answer": "PAF"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "A mission to organize, train, and equip naval forces for the naval combat?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["AFP", "PA", "PN", "PAF"],
    "answer": "PN"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "To uphold the sovereignty, support the Constitution and defend the republic against all enemies, foreign and domestic?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["AFP", "PA", "PN", "PAF"],
    "answer": "AFP"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "A Philippine Army unit that serve for the reservist and retiree affairs?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Combat unit", "AFP", "ARESCOM", "Philippine navy"],
    "answer": "ARESCOM"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Who is the Commanding General of Philippine Army?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["LIUETENANT GENERAL MACAIROG S ALBERTO AFP", "GENERAL MACAIROG S ALBERTO AFP", "LIUETENANT GENERAL MACAIROG S ALBERTO", "LIUETENANT MACAIROG S ALBERTO AFP"],
    "answer": "LIUETENANT GENERAL MACAIROG S ALBERTO"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "What is OJ3 in joint coordinating staff of AFP?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["intelligence", "CMO", "OPERATIONS", "Logistics"],
    "answer": "OPERATIONS"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Which is not belong to the joint coordinating staff of AFP?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Logistics", "ENGINEERING", "Operations", "Intelligence"],
    "answer": "ENGINEERING"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Who is the commander in Chief of AFP?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["RODRIGO DUTERTE", "HIS EXCELLENCY PRESIDENT RODRIGO ROA DUTERTE", "Pres, RODRIGO ROA", "PRESIDENT RODRIGO DUTERTE"],
    "answer": "HIS EXCELLENCY PRESIDENT RODRIGO ROA DUTERTE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Which is not belong to AFP Major Services",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["PAGASA", "PA", "PAF", "PN"],
    "answer": "PAGASA"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Secretary of National Defense is part of AFP Organization?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "RCDG is known as regional Community Defense Center?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "BRIGADEIR GENERAL BERNIE S LANGUB AFP is the commanding General of ARESCOM?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Lt. Nisperos is the First Philippine Airforce Pilot?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Our President Rodrigo Roa Duterte is also the Commander in Chief of the AFP?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "LIUETENANT GENERAL MACAIROG S ALBERTO AFP is the Commanding General of Philippine Army?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "MAJOR GENERAL JESUS B SARSAGAT AFP is the Chief of staff of AFP?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "The Mission of AFP is Serving the people, securing the land.?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "To defend the Republic of the Philippines, safeguards its national security, and to assist government agencies in the socio-economic development of the country. Is the AFP Vision?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 2,
    "question": "Uphold the sovereignty, support the Constitution and defend the territory of the country. Is one of the Function of AFP?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "Consist of a systems patrols and fixed posts",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Main Guard"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "In order to preserve, protect property and enforce military regulations in all military installations, the interior guard system is installed by the commanders.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Interior Guard Duty"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "a secret word or sound used to answer the challenge.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Password"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO TAKE CHARGE OF THIS POST AND ALL GOVERNMENT PROPERTY IN VIEW. Is what GO?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "1|GO1"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "extra member of the guard.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Supernumenary"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "a special password used as a check on the countersign.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Parole"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO TALK TO NO ONE EXCEPT IN LINE OF DUTY. Is what GO?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "7|GO7"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO GIVE ALARM IN CASE OF FIRE OR DISORDER.Is what GO?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "8|GO8"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "Requires a band and is held in the parade ground of the unit from which the guards are detailed.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FORMAL GUARD MOUNTING"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO REPEAT ALL CALLS FROM POST MORE DISTANCE FROM THE GUARD HOUSE THAN MY OWN. Is what GO?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "4|GO4"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "a secret challenge and a password issued by higher headquarters to ensure scrutiny of acceptable persons to pass the lines.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Password", "Countersign", "Challenge", "Parole"],
    "answer": "Countersign"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "\"halt who is there\" or a secret challenge in words or sounds.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Challenge", "Sergeant of the guard (SOG)", "Parole", "Password"],
    "answer": "Password"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "This is held in the parade ground of the unit from which the guards are detailed.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Special orders", "Sergeant of the guard (SOG)", "Parole", "Informal Guard Mounting"],
    "answer": "Informal Guard Mounting"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO SALUTE ALL OFFICERS AND COLORS IN STANDARD NOT CASE.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["GO1", "GO11", "GO7", "GO10"],
    "answer": "GO10"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "specified area for which the assigned guard is responsible.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Guard's Post", "GO11", "Parole", "Password"],
    "answer": "Guard's Post"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO REPORT ALL VIOLATION OF ORDERS I AM INSTRUCTED TO ENFORCE.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["GO11", "GO2", "GO3", "GO5"],
    "answer": "GO3"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "an officer acting directly under the CO. he is responsible for the execution of all orders and other duties on a given day.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Relief Commander", "Supernumenary", "Commander guard of the day", "Parole"],
    "answer": "Commander guard of the day"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO WALK MY POST IN MILITARY MANNER KEEPING ALWAYS ON THE ALERT AND OBSERVING EVRYTHING THAT TAKES PLACE WITH SIGHT AND HEARING.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["GO2", "GO3", "GO6", "GO9"],
    "answer": "GO2"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO CALL THE COMMANDER OF THE RELIEF IN ANY CASE NOT COVERED BY INSTRUCTION.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["GO11", "GO7", "GO4", "GO9"],
    "answer": "GO9"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "Generally in combat zone or outside permanent military installations such as lookouts, listening post etc.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["External Guard Duty", "Main Guard", "Special Guard", "Interior Guard"],
    "answer": "External Guard Duty"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "RELIEF COMMANDERS (RC) is the senior non-commission officer?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO BE SPECIALY WATCHFUL AT NIGHT DURING THE TIME OF CHALLENGING AND TO CHALLENGE ALL PERSONS ON OR NEAR MY POST AND TO ALLOW NO ONE TO PASS WITHOUT PROPER AUTHORITY. Is GO 11?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "SPECIAL ORDERS - orders given to a particular guard in a particular post, orders carefully tailored for a specific post, time measured, easily off or on and for a short time.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "TO RECEIVE, OBEY AND PASS ON THE SENTINNEL WHO RELIEFS ME ALL ORDERS FROM COMMANDING OFFICER, OFFICER OF THE DAY AND NON-COMMISSIONED OFFICER OF THE GUARD ONLY. Is GO7?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "SPECIAL GUARDS is for special security purposes?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "The two types of Guard Duties are Interior Guard Duty and Main Guard?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "The extra member of the guard is called SUPERNUMENARY?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "COUNTERSIGNS AND PAROLE WORDS is the CO directs this and ensure that any person in time of war who discloses the countersigns or parole to any person not entitled to received shall be punished with death or such punishment that the court-marital may direct (Military Justice Art.101)?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "Challenge is a secret word or sound used to answer the challenge?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 3,
    "question": "INTERIOR GUARD DUTY in which will be the focused?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "a state of order and obedience existing within a command",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Military Discipline"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "It is the highest form of military courtesy",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Salute"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "It is always associated with punishment",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "DISCIPLINE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "wholesome relationships between juniors and seniors, between young and old, with all persons.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Military Courtesy"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Sergeants are addressed as?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Sgt"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Lieutenants are addressed officially as?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Lieutenants"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "A First Sergeant is addressed as",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "F/Sgt"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "JUNIORS in the organization are always expected the proper courtesy to the?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Seniors"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Cadets are addressed as?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Cadet"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Use of third person by an officer is of poor taste is a?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "taboos"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Which of the following situations a soldier is not required to salute?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["When at work", "After conversing an Officer", "When national color Passes by", "Meeting an Officer"],
    "answer": "When at work"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "When walking with seniors, the junior stays at the-",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Right side", "Left side", "In between seniors", "Both a & c"],
    "answer": "Left side"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Which situation should a soldier render salute?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Meeting opposing force Officer", "When indoors", "After conversing with an Officer", "When attending to a vehicle"],
    "answer": "After conversing with an Officer"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "It is the state of order and obedience existing within a command-",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military Courtesy", "Military Discipline", "Military Leadership", "Military Professionalism"],
    "answer": "Military Discipline"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Which is a taboo in the military service?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Excessive indebtedness", "Calling people by name", "Entering a clubhouse", "Sleeping during vigil"],
    "answer": "Excessive indebtedness"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "What is the courtesy rendered in entering a boat or automobile?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Senior enters first, leaves last", "Junior enters first, leaves last", "Senior is last to enter, leaves first", "Junior last to enter, leaves first"],
    "answer": "Senior enters first, leaves last"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "It is always associated with punishment. There are rules, however on how to use punishment.?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Courtesy", "Discipline", "Taboos", "Military Discipline"],
    "answer": "Discipline"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "wholesome relationships between juniors and seniors, between young and old, with all persons.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military Courtesy", "Military Discipline", "Military Professionalism", "Discipline"],
    "answer": "Military Courtesy"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Sergeant Majors are addressed as?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Cadet", "Cpl", "Sgt Major", "F/Sgt"],
    "answer": "Sgt Major"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "For cadets, they are addressed as?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Cadet", "Cpl", "Pvt", "Sgt"],
    "answer": "Cadet"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Lieutenants are addressed officially as lieutenants?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "There are eleven Taboos",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "THE NATIONAL FLAG AND THE NATIONAL ANTHEM likewise requires an appropriate courtesy.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "A person saluting looks at the person saluted.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Offer no excuses is part of salute",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "SALUTE is not the highest form of military courtesy.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Sir will be used in addressing a female officer.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Covered or uncovered, salute is rendered in the usual manner.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Military Courtesy is a state of order and obedience existing within a command",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 4,
    "question": "Corporals are addressed as Cpl?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "written communication whereby the AFP Transact most of its business. It concerns every subject and takes many forms.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Military Correspondence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is a reply of forwarding statement added to Military letter.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Endorsement"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It a written communication having two folds purposes (to convey information/to build goodwill).",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Correspondence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is an informal communication sent through wire services to facilitate action on a certain matter.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Radio Message"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is an informal communication sent through wire services to facilitate one to another within headquarters.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Routing Slip"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is intended for use to initiate personal actions.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Personal Action Form"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "this part consists of all the materials above the first line in the body.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "HEADING"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is the body of military letter is those part that placed between the heading and the close.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Body"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "the close of military letter consists of the command or authority line, signature element and enclosure block.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "CLOSED"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is used for correspondence with the Sec. of National Defense, other government departments, civilian agencies and civilians.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Non - Military (Personal Type)"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Top of the letterhead is normally placing 3/4 inch or in the 5th line below the top edge of the paper.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Date", "Letterhead", "Subject", "Attention Address"],
    "answer": "Letterhead"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is usual order is the day, the month and the year will the day and the year in numerical, while the month is spelled out.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Date", "Letterhead", "Subject", "Attention Address"],
    "answer": "Date"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "The subject of military letter should be stated briefly and directly, not exceeding 10 words.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Date", "Letterhead", "Subject", "Attention Address"],
    "answer": "Subject"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "To speed routing, correspondence may be addressed to the attention of an individual of the head.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Date", "Letterhead", "Subject", "Attention Address"],
    "answer": "Attention Address"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "identifying file references is placed at the left margin, usually two (2) spaces below the letterhead and in line with the date.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Date", "Letterhead", "Subject", "File References"],
    "answer": "File References"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "single line spacing with double line spacing between paragraph is used except when the communication is very short.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Line Spacing", "Paragraphing", "Dividing Paragraph", "Date"],
    "answer": "Line Spacing"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "The second and succeeding lines will begin at left margin.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Line Spacing", "Paragraphing", "Dividing Paragraph", "Margin"],
    "answer": "Paragraphing"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "It is a paragraph of three or fewer lines will not be divided between pages.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Line Spacing", "Paragraphing", "Dividing Paragraph", "Margin"],
    "answer": "Dividing Paragraph"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "used in lieu of the command or authority line signature and enclosure are also included.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Body", "Style", "Closed", "Margin"],
    "answer": "Closed"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Paragraphs are not numbered, single spacing is authorized when the letters contain more than 9 lines.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Body", "Style", "Closed", "Margin"],
    "answer": "Body"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Style follows the same general style of civilian business letter in the following aspects. It uses a salutation, which is a part of the heading, and a complementary close, which is a part of the close.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Style, Body, and Closed are types of Non-Military (Personal Types) Letters",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "The part of Margins are Top, Top, Left, Right, and Bottom.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Letter is generally the same as that Military (subject) letter.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Endorsement letter expressions forming the body of the Endorsement letter.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "The stamped and checked It is used to forward communication without comment.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Correspondence written communication whereby the AFP Transact most of its business. It concerns every subject and takes many forms.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "Personal Action Form is intended for use to initiate personal actions.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 5,
    "question": "The three main elements of Letter are Heading, Body, Close (Complementary Ending).",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Is the process of influencing others to accomplish the mission by proving direct purpose and motivation",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Military Leadership"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Personal qualities that are direct value to the Commander in gaining the willing obedience, conference respect and loyal cooperation of his men in accomplishing a mission.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Leadership Traits"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Fundamental guidelines for the selection of appropriate action and orders in the proper exercise of the Command",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Leadership Principles"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Authority which an individual in the Military service lawfully exercises over subordinates by virtue of Ranks and assignments or position.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Command"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Refers to that process whereby an individual directs guide, influences or control the thoughts, feeling or behavior of another human being.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Leadership"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "It is the mental state and spirit of an individual unit.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Morale"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "It is the common spirit reflected by all members of a unit and provides group solidarity.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Esprit de corps"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "is the attitude that ensures prompt obedience to order and the initiatives of appropriate action in the absence of order.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Discipline"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "is the technical, tactical, and physical ability to do the job well.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Proficiency"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "A man's bearing is his general appearance, carriage, deportment and conduct.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Bearing"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "It is the promptness of making a decision in a state of clear and forceful manner.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Judgment", "Decisiveness", "Justice", "Knowledge"],
    "answer": "Decisiveness"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Is a mental quality that recognize fear of danger or criticism, but enables a man to proceed in the face of it with calmness and firmness",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Courage", "Decisiveness", "Justice", "Knowledge"],
    "answer": "Courage"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "The certainly proper performance of duty, is a quality the leader must develop.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Courage", "Decisiveness", "Dependability", "Knowledge"],
    "answer": "Dependability"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "The mental and physical stamina measured by the ability of withstand pain fatigue, stress and hardship is kin to courage",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Courage", "Decisiveness", "Dependability", "Endurance"],
    "answer": "Endurance"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Is the display of sincere interest and zeal in the performance of duties. This requires the leader to be optimistic and cheerful.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Enthusiasm", "Decisiveness", "Dependability", "Endurance"],
    "answer": "Enthusiasm"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Initiative or taking action in the absence of orders, is often required of leaders.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Enthusiasm", "Decisiveness", "Dependability", "Initiative"],
    "answer": "Initiative"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "The uprightness and soundness of moral principles, the quality of truthfulness and honesty describe integrity.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Enthusiasm", "Integrity", "Dependability", "Initiative"],
    "answer": "Integrity"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Is the ability to logically weigh facts and possible solution on which to be sound decision.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Enthusiasm", "Integrity", "Judgement", "Initiative"],
    "answer": "Judgement"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Loyalty is the quality of faithfulness to country, the Army, seniors, subordinates and peers.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Loyalty Is the ability to deal with others in a respectful manner.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Unselfishness is the unselfish leader is one who avoid providing his own comfort and personal advancement at the expense of others.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "The Basic Responsibilities of a Commander are Accomplishment of the Mission and Welfare of the men?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Military Leadership Is the process of influencing others to accomplish the mission by proving direct purpose and motivation",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Leadership Traits is a Traits of a Good Leader?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Leadership is an authority which an individual in the Military service lawfully exercises over subordinates by virtue of Ranks and assignments or position.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Morale, Esprit De Corps, Discipline, Proficiency are Leadership Indicators?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Self-Improvement is basic Responsibilities of a Commander",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 6,
    "question": "Leadership is not inherent is a concept of Military Leadership",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Those rights, which are inherent in our nature, and without which, we cannot live as human beings.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Human Rights"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "No person, not even the state authority, has the right to take the life of a person except in the cases of heinous crimes what penalty is this?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Death Penalty"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Whether intentional or unintentional expulsion of the fetus from the woman's womb before the term of its viability is another violation of the right to life.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Abortion"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "\"No one shall be subjected to arbitrary or unlawful interference with his privacy, family, home or correspondence, nor to unlawful attacks on his honor and reputation.\" (Art. 17, sec. 1, covenant).",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Right to Privacy|Privacy Right"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "\"No one shall be liable to be tried or punished again for an offence for which he has already been finally convicted or acquitted in accordance with the law and penal procedure of each country.\" (art 14, sec. 7, political covenant.)",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "DOUBLE JEOPARDY"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Bail. Is a security filed by an accused for his temporary release (rule 114, rules, of court)? An accused is entitled to bail except when he is charged of a crime punishable by life or death sentence and the evidence is strong (art. Ii, sec. 13, Philippine constitution). What right is this?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Right to Bail"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "The right of the accused to meet the witnesses face to face is intended to give the accused the opportunity to cross-examine them. The said provisions are implanted in more detail under Rule 113 of the Rules of court of the Philippines. What right is this?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Right of Confrontation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "There are instances when any state police officer or private person, without judicial warrant, may arrest a person who, (1) has committed or is actually committing, or attempting to commit an offense in his presence (2) when an offense was committed and he has personal knowledge that the person to be arrested has committed the offense, (3) a prisoner who has escaped. (Rule 113, sec. 5, rules of court.)",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Warrantless Arrest"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "\"All persons are equal before the law and are entitled without any discrimination to the equal protection of the law\" (art. 26, political covenant).",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Equality before the Law"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Forced or compulsory labor is not absolutely prohibited.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Exception on forced labor"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "It includes the right to freely determine their political status and to pursue their economic, social and cultural development (art. I, sec.1).",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Death Penalty", "Right of self - Determination", "Abortion", "Warrantless Arrest"],
    "answer": "Right of self - Determination"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "While freedom gives man the right to make moral decisions, he is responsible for doing so and has to answer to his own conscience",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Man's Responsibility", "Right of self - Determination", "Abortion", "Warrantless Arrest"],
    "answer": "Man's Responsibility"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Human rights are supreme, inherent and inalienable rights to life, dignity and self-development.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Death Penalty", "Right of self - Determination", "Abortion", "Philippine commission"],
    "answer": "Philippine commission"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "The following are Basic characteristics of Human Rights except?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Inherent", "Fundamental", "Dependent", "Indivisible"],
    "answer": "Dependent"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "It is maintaining checkpoints are some street corners and searching a person passing or stopping a vehicle to conduct searches has been constituted as violation human rights.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military or police checkpoint", "Fundamental", "Dependent", "Indivisible"],
    "answer": "Military or police checkpoint"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "It is maintaining checkpoints are some street corners and searching a person passing or stopping a vehicle to conduct searches has been constituted as violation human rights.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military or police checkpoint", "Fundamental", "Dependent", "Indivisible"],
    "answer": "Military or police checkpoint"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "It is maintaining checkpoints are some street corners and searching a person passing or stopping a vehicle to conduct searches has been constituted as violation human rights.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military or police checkpoint", "Fundamental", "Dependent", "Indivisible"],
    "answer": "Military or police checkpoint"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Promulgated by the U.S supreme court in Miranda vs. Arizona, 384 U.S. 436 in (1960)?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military or police checkpoint", "Public Trial", "Miranda Doctrine", "Indivisible"],
    "answer": "Miranda Doctrine"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "No one shall be subjected to arbitrary or unlawful interference with his privacy, family, home or correspondence, nor to unlawful attacks on his honor and reputation.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Right to Bail", "Right to compensation Due to Miscarriage of Justice", "Miranda Doctrine", "Right to privacy"],
    "answer": "Right to privacy"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "A statute which renders a previously innocent act a criminal offense, aggravates or increases the punishment for a crime or alters the rules of evidence, or deprives an accused of some protection or defense previously available.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Ex post facto law", "Equality before the law", "Miranda Doctrine", "Right to privacy"],
    "answer": "Ex post facto law"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Any person arrested by police or military authorities should be informed, at the time of arrest, of the reasons of his arrest.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Right of the arrested or detained person", "Equality before the law", "Miranda Doctrine", "Right to privacy"],
    "answer": "Right of the arrested or detained person"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "It is the right of the accused to meet the witnesses face to face is intended to give the accused the opportunity to cross-examine them.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Right of the arrested or detained person", "Right of Confrontation", "Right to Bail", "Right to privacy"],
    "answer": "Right of Confrontation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Special procedures for juveniles IN the case of the juvenile person, the procedure shall be such as will take account of their age and the desirability of promoting their rehabilitation",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Ex post facto law means a statute which renders a previously innocent act a criminal offense, aggravates or increases the punishment for a crime or alters the rules of evidence, or deprives an accused of some protection or defense previously available.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Euthanasia-mercy killing Whether intentional or unintentional expulsion of the fetus from the woman's womb before the term of its viability is another violation of the right to life.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Abortion No person, not even the state authority, has the right to take the life of a person except in the cases of heinous crimes.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "The Basic characteristics of Human Rights Human rights are generally characterized as inherent, fundamental, inalienable, imprescriptibly, indivisible, universal and interdependent.?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Arbitrary arrest and detention where Everyone has the right to liberty and security of person.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Right to Life, Liberty and Security is the most basic human rights from which other rights flow is the right to life.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Prohibition of slavery and involuntary servitude. Slavery has been a legalized institution since the ancient Roman law period. Article 8 of the covenant states No one shall be held in slavery and slave trade in all forms shall be prohibited. Involuntary servitude - forced labor.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Right to Appeal One's conviction of a Crime Everyone convicted of a crime shall have the right to his conviction and sentence being reviewed by a higher tribunal according to law.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 7,
    "question": "Human rights are generally defined as those rights, which are inherent in our nature, and without which, we cannot live as human beings.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Immediate treatment administered to a victim of injury or illness before the services of a doctor or corpsman can be obtained.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "First Aid"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "If a casualty stops breathing you must give artificial respiration immediately. This is?",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Restore Breathing"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Results from scraping (abrading) the skin. Bleeding is minimal and limited to ruptured small veins and capillaries.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Abrasions"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Cuts, commonly caused by sharp objects the degree of bleeding depends on the deep and extent of a cut.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Incised Wound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Jagged, irregular or blunt breaks or tears in the skin. The destruction of tissues is greater in.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Lacerated Wound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "irregularly caused by pointed objects such as pin, icepick, nails and splinters. - external bleeding is usually minor, but the fracturing object may penetrate deeply into the body and thus damage organs and cause severe internal bleeding.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Fracture wound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Involve forcible separation or tearing or tissue from the victims' body. commonly caused by animal's bites and accidents involving motor vehicles and heavy machinery.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Avulsions"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "It is a continuation of blood flowing from the wounds.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Bleeding"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "The healing process is delayed by infection.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Infections"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Any break in the continuity of the skin/tissue of the body.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Wound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "There is a break in the skin or mucus membrane.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Close Fracture", "Open Wound", "Close Wound", "Fracture"],
    "answer": "Open Wound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Involves underlying tissues without a break in the skin or mucus Membrane.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Close Fracture", "Open Wound", "Close Wound", "Fracture"],
    "answer": "Close Wound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "No break in the continuity or no injury to the skin. It is free from air and infection.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Close Fracture", "Open Wound", "Close Wound", "Fracture"],
    "answer": "Close Fracture"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "One in which, there is wound communicating with the broken ends of the bone is broken into more than two (2) pieces.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Close Fracture", "Open Wound", "Close Wound", "Open Fracture"],
    "answer": "Open Fracture"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Has elliptical eyes and leave two (2) fang marked.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Close Fracture", "Poisonous Snake Bite", "Non- Poisonous Snake Bite", "Open Fracture"],
    "answer": "Poisonous Snake Bite"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Has around eyes and single fang marked.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Close Fracture", "Poisonous Snake Bite", "Non- Poisonous Snake Bite", "Open Fracture"],
    "answer": "Non- Poisonous Snake Bite"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Involve the superficial layer of the skin, healing occurs rapidly. It is redness, swelling and pain.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["First Degree Burns", "Second Degree Burns", "Third Degree Burns", "Fourth Degree Burns"],
    "answer": "First Degree Burns"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Involve complete loss of all layers of the skin.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["First Degree Burns", "Second Degree Burns", "Third Degree Burns", "Fourth Degree Burns"],
    "answer": "Third Degree Burns"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Deeper than first degree burns, blister formation, considerable swelling, more painful because the nerve ending is destroyed in 3rd degree burns.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["First Degree Burns", "Second Degree Burns", "Third Degree Burns", "Fourth Degree Burns"],
    "answer": "Second Degree Burns"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "An injury that result from heat, chemical agents or radiation.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Fracture", "Bite", "Wounds", "Burns"],
    "answer": "Burns"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Poisoning is any substance solid, liquid or gas that tends to impair health and it cause death when introduced into the body.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Mouth to mouth (nose) method is the standard method of artificial respiration are the mouth-to-mouth, the chest pressure and back pressure arm lift methods",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Cardiopulmonary resuscitation this is a life-support technique that is used in a medical emergency when the victim is not breathing and when it is possible that his heart has stopped beating.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "The mouth-to-mouth (also mouth to nose) method is considered to be more effective and reliable. In restoring to this method, a first aider should follow certain steps or procedures",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Hyperventilation where muscles undergo marked spasm and would totally incapacitates a swimmer because of severe pain.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Cramps gives excessive deep breathing of the lungs before swimming under water, the carbon dioxide concentration of the blood is lowered by the forced exhaling of air during deep breathing.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Drowning is an aspiration of fluids or obstruction of the airway caused by spasm of the larynx in the water.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "There are two primary methods for administering artificial respiration.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Compound or Open Fracture and Simple or Close Fracture are the two classes of Fracture.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 8,
    "question": "Mouth-to-Mouth Method the same procedure was made or should be done. But instead of mouth, close his nose with your thumb and fore finger.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is the basic in training the soldier to employ successfully the pistol or the rifle in combat.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Marksmanship"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is the technique of teaching of personnel on how to fire the weapon accurately and employ it in combat.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Marksmanship Training"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The firer is concerned with correct pointing his pistol or rifle so that the projectile will hit the target when he fires.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Aiming"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is obtained when the front sight and rear sight are properly aligned to the target and aiming point is the correct relationship to the front sight blade.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Sight Picture"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is the target on which you are aligned your sight.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Aiming Point"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is the independent action of the forefinger on the trigger pulling, it straight to the rear with uniformly increasing pressure until the weapon fired.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Trigger Control"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This is the firer reaction of the anticipated recoil of the exploding round.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Flinching"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This is an attempt by the firer to take-up the recoil just before the weapon fires by tensing his shoulder muscles and moving the shoulder forward.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Bucking"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This is an attempt by the firer to make rifle fire at a certain time by rapidly applying pressure on the trigger.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Jerking"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is the continued mental and physical application of the fundamental after each round has been fired.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Follow Through"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The following are the factors which affect holding a rifle steady except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Relaxation", "Trigger Control", "Taking up the Slack", "Grip of the left hand"],
    "answer": "Taking up the Slack"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This position presents a low silhouette and easily adopted for the use of cover and support.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Standing Position", "Prone Position", "Kneeling Position", "Foxhole"],
    "answer": "Prone Position"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This position is used whenever prepared positions are available.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Standing Position", "Prone Position", "Kneeling Position", "Foxhole"],
    "answer": "Foxhole"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This position is used in the assault to engage surprise target and when no other position can be used.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Standing Position", "Prone Position", "Kneeling Position", "Foxhole"],
    "answer": "Standing Position"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This position is suitable for use at live ground that slope gently upward.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Standing Position", "Prone Position", "Kneeling Position", "Foxhole"],
    "answer": "Kneeling Position"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This position will enable the firer to fire across obstacles and low walls.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Standing Position", "Prone Position", "Kneeling Position", "Sitting Position"],
    "answer": "Sitting Position"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "This position is an excellent position to be used in a mud, shallow water or contaminated area.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Standing Position", "Prone Position", "Squatting Position", "Sitting Position"],
    "answer": "Squatting Position"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The following are the marksmanship principles except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Controlled Breathing", "Trigger Release", "Follow Through", "Jerking"],
    "answer": "Jerking"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "It is conducted before firing live rounds. During day firing, the soldier should practice sight alignment and placement of the aiming point.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Aiming Practice", "Sight Picture", "Follow Through", "Aiming Point"],
    "answer": "Aiming Practice"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The top of the front sight blade is exactly in the center of the rear sight aperture.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Aiming Practice", "Sight Alignment", "Follow Through", "Aiming Point"],
    "answer": "Sight Alignment"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The Type of trigger for rifle 5.56 mm M16A1 are Semi-automatic fire trigger control and Automatic fire trigger control.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "Position and hold must be firm enough to support the weapon are on of the parts of Marksmanship Principles.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "Consider the rifle or pistol LOADED at all times, even in the break areas. Never point the pistol or rifle to anyone you not want to hurt.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The coach and coach method of instruction is peculiarly applicable the training in marksmanship",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "All loading and unloading are executed on the firing line with the muscle of the rifle or pistol pointing towards the target. Strictly no loading behind the firing line.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The elements of Correct Sight Picture are Aiming Practice and Aiming Point.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "There are seven (7) standard Firing Position.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "Flinching, Bucking, Jerking are indication of proper trigger control.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "The components of integrated acts of Shooting are Aiming, and Steady Hold Factor.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 9,
    "question": "Marksmanship Training is the basic in training the soldier to employ successfully the pistol or the rifle in combat.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "One of the oldest and most reliable method of transmitting intelligence. This is the most secured means of communication.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Messenger"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "another means of physical communication.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Mail"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "one of the most efficient trained animals in the field of communication.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Trained Animal"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "The bulk our communications worn always are carried by telecommunication.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Telecommunication means"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "It is the principal means of communication in many tactical units.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Radio"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "one of the principal means of communication and includes the use of field wire, cable assemblies, wire laying and recovery, sound powered and battery-operated telephone, switchboard, typewriter and associated equipment.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Wire"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "This is a supplementary means of communication that is available to all units.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Sound"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "communication are means available to all units and used for transmitting (a combination of audio) as well as recognition of friendly forces among the medium use for this particular means of communication.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Visual"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Medium by which communication is conveyed from one person or place or another.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Basic signal Communication"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Is a method or means of conveying information from one person or place top another except by direct conversation.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Signal Communication"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "This is the though or idea that the originator wishes to express.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Message", "Body", "Brevity", "Standing operation of Procedure"],
    "answer": "Body"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Is a though or idea, express in brief, in plain or secret language and prepare in a form suitable or transmission by any means of communication.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Message", "Body", "Brevity", "Standing operation of Procedure"],
    "answer": "Message"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "What is U in Phonetic Alphabet?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["UNIVERSITY", "UNATTENDED", "UNNIE", "UNIFORM"],
    "answer": "UNIFORM"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Is a set of instructions covering features of operation which lend themselves to a definite or standardized procedure.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Message", "Body", "Brevity", "Standing operation of Procedure"],
    "answer": "Standing operation of Procedure"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "What is F in Phonetic Alphabet?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["FRUIT", "FLAMINGO", "FOXTROT", "FAN"],
    "answer": "FOXTROT"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "The following are advantages of Visual except one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["suitable for short pre-arranged message", "suitable for short distance", "vulnerable to interception", "does not require sophisticated installation"],
    "answer": "vulnerable to interception"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "What is A in the Phonetic Alphabet?",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["APPLE", "ALPHA", "ABS", "ALPHE"],
    "answer": "ALPHA"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "The following are advantages of Radio except one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Speed of Installation", "Integrated with wire", "Flexibility", "Least Secured"],
    "answer": "Least Secured"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "The text of a message should be clear accurate and brief.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Message", "Body", "Brevity", "Standing operation of Procedure"],
    "answer": "Brevity"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Is a facility which embraces the personnel and equipment necessary to provide signal communication by any particular means of combination thereof.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Office of the President", "ALPHA Agency", "School Office", "Agency of signal Communication"],
    "answer": "Agency of signal Communication"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Transmit only when necessary or emergency. Is Part of Tactical Applications.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Messenger this is by mail forwarding of messages by an established postal system.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "The word telecommunication is derived from the Greek combining far, for off or broadly, operating at a distance.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Signal communication Is a method or means of conveying information from one person or place top another except by direct conversation.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Wire They are used chiefly to attract attention, pre-arranged message, and speed alarm.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Messenger may be classified as to type of service into special and scheduled messenger service, as to made of transport into motor, foot, or air relative rate of speed.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Vulnerable to interception, subject to initiative deception, and stations depend on the line of sight location are advantages of Visual.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Sound signal are transmitted by WHISTLES, BUGLES, HORNS, GONGS, KLAXONS, WEAPON and other noise making devices.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "Trained Animal one of the most efficient trained animals in the field of communication.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 10,
    "question": "C in Phonetic Alphabet means CHARLIE.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "It is a person, thing or activity from which information is originally obtained.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Source"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "is the end product resulting from the collection, evaluation, analysis, integration and interpretation of all available information.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Intelligence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "It is to make systematic examination or to conduct an official inquiry.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Investigation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "is any unevaluated data for every description which when processed may produce intelligence.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Information"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Complete and accurate awareness of individual in his/her surroundings.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Observation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "The art of questioning and examining a source to obtain a maximum amount of usable information.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Interrogation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Information is obtained from another person who is aware that he/she is giving information.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Interview"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "It is consisting of collection, evaluation, interpretation and dissemination of information pertaining to possible or actual enemy operation.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Military Intelligence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Obtaining information from a person who is unaware that he/she is providing wanted information.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Elicitation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Timely transmission of information and or/ intelligence in an appropriate form and by any suitable means to those who need it.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Dissemination"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Is the knowledge of people, weather, enemy and terrain or geographical features required by a Commander in the planning and conduct of tactical operations.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Combat Intelligence", "Strategic Intelligence", "Counterintelligence", "Military Intelligence"],
    "answer": "Combat Intelligence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Is the knowledge which requiring to serve as basis for the formulation of policy and military plans at national and international level.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Combat Intelligence", "Strategic Intelligence", "Counterintelligence", "Military Intelligence"],
    "answer": "Strategic Intelligence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "The aspect of military intelligence relating to all security control measures both active and passive designed to ensure safeguarding of information and materials, personnel and installation sabotage, espionage and subversive activities of foreign powers.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Combat Intelligence", "Strategic Intelligence", "Counterintelligence", "Military Intelligence"],
    "answer": "Counterintelligence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "It is the product resulting from the collection, evaluation, and interpretation of information which concerns one or more aspects of foreign nations or of functional or geographic areas.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Combat Intelligence", "Strategic Intelligence", "Counterintelligence", "Intelligence"],
    "answer": "Intelligence"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Is the systematic exploitation of sources of by collecting agencies of the delivery of the information obtained to the proper intelligence section.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Collection", "Strategic Intelligence", "Source of Information", "Collection Agency"],
    "answer": "Collection"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Any person, unit or activity that called or process information by research, surveillance, interrogation or other exploitation of resources.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Collection", "Strategic Intelligence", "Source of Information", "Collection Agency"],
    "answer": "Collection Agency"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Are persons, things or action from which information about the enemy, whether or terrain is derived.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Collection", "Strategic Intelligence", "Source of Information", "Collection Agency"],
    "answer": "Source of Information"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Is the step which intelligence is created from the raw material of information.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Collection", "Strategic Intelligence", "Processing", "Evaluation"],
    "answer": "Processing"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Information is of small value unless it has been analyzed to respect to its pertinence, the reliability of the officer and agency and its probable accuracy.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Collection", "Strategic Intelligence", "Processing", "Evaluation"],
    "answer": "Evaluation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Measures taken by a certain unit to protect itself from espionage, hostile observation, subversion or sabotage",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Military Cycle", "Military Information", "Military Intelligence", "Military Security"],
    "answer": "Military Security"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "There are three (3) Types of Military Intelligence.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Planning the collection effort, Collection of Information, Processing Information, and Dissemination and use are the four (4) Phases of Intelligence Cycle.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Military Security – is consists of collection, evaluation, interpretation and dissemination of information pertaining to possible or actual enemy operation.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Intelligence cycle- Is a study in which phase is considered first information or intelligence can be inserted in any phase as appropriate. The intel Cycle has no beginning and no end.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Concealment and camouflage is one of the examples of military Security.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Military information- Means all facts, documents, materials, photographs, diagrams, maps, and reports of observations of any kind which increases our knowledge of a possible or actual enemy or area of operations",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Counter Intelligence is the knowledge which requiring to serve as basis for the formulation of policy and military plans at national and international level.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Information is unevaluated material of every description including that derived from observations, communications, reports, rumors, imagery, and other sources from which intelligence is produced.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "Processing Is the step which intelligence is created from the raw material of information.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 11,
    "question": "There are 15 fifteen examples of Military Security.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "It is the ability to outlive danger or death, the will and determination to live.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Survival"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "The advances in the development of outdoor clothing, equipment's, emergency food and techniques have been growing rapidly.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Preparedness"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "This will protect the body from outside elements (heat, cold, rain, snow, sun, wind, etc.) and harmful insects",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Shelter"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "First-aid Kit include blanket to attend to bruises, scrapers, cuts, burns, and keep body protected.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "First-Aid"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "To make contact with possible rescuer or potential help via building a triangular fires, smoke, flashlight, bright colored clothing and other markers such as: reflective mirror, whistles, gunshot, stick, signal, and others.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Signaling"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Always bring extra food and water especially if your is longer than anticipated.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Food and Water"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Is the number one enemy in an emergency situation be it, lost stranded or injured.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Panic"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "it provides warmth, light, and comfort by keeping body temperature or body core heat on the average",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Knowing how to build a fire"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "All seaweeds, eggs, and reptiles are edible",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Rules of Survival"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Panic, Boredom, Pain, Hunger, Cold, Thirst.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Enemies of Survival"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "The following are enemies of Survival except one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Chilin", "Cold", "Hunger", "Panic"],
    "answer": "Chilin"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "It include blanket to attend to bruises, scrapers, cuts, burns, and keep body protected.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Chilin", "Foods", "Shelter", "First-Aid"],
    "answer": "Chilin"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "This will protect the body from outside elements (heat, cold, rain, snow, sun, wind, etc.) and harmful insects",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Panic", "Foods", "Shelter", "First-Aid"],
    "answer": "Shelter"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "The following are enemies of Survival except one",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Boredom", "Fatigue", "Thirst", "happiness"],
    "answer": "happiness"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "The following are survival Remember except one",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Act like Native, blend locally", "Learn by heart the basic survival skills", "Have fun", "Vanquish fear and panic, keep cool"],
    "answer": "Have fun"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "It is the ability to outlive danger or death, the will and determination to live.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Shelter", "Survival", "Thirst", "happiness"],
    "answer": "Survival"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Fire keeps away the harmful creatures, purify water and cook food.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Shelter", "Survival", "Knowing how to build fire", "Signaling"],
    "answer": "Knowing how to build fire"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "To make contact with possible rescuer or potential help via building a triangular fire, smoke, flashlight, bright colored clothing and other.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Shelter", "Survival", "Knowing how to build fire", "Signaling"],
    "answer": "Signaling"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Things that can be eaten by birds and monkeys alike can be consumed by man",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Enemies of Survival", "Rules of Survival", "Survival Reminders", "Survival"],
    "answer": "Rules of Survival"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Fear/Panic, Pain, Cold, Thirst, Hunger, Fatigue, Loneliness/ Boredom.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Enemies of Survival", "Rules of Survival", "Survival Reminders", "Survival"],
    "answer": "Enemies of Survival"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Things that can be eaten by birds and monkeys alike can be consumed by man",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Anything that flies, include airborne matters can be eaten.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Anything that swim is edible.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "All seaweeds, eggs, and reptiles are edible.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "All four-legged animals can be eaten",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Anything that creeps and crawls is edible",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Enjoyment is the ability to outlive danger or death, the will and determination to live.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "There are (5) five basic survival skills needed in nearly all situations.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Remember and locate present position and employ skill in map reading is one of the survival reminders?",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 12,
    "question": "Survival is the advances in the development of outdoor clothing, equipment's, emergency food and techniques have been growing rapidly.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "It is science that deals with health and its maintenance.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Hygiene"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "It is a measure for the protection of public health.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Sanitation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The state of individual who enjoys physical, mental and social well-being.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Health"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "deals with these measures taken by the individual to preserve his own health.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Personal Hygiene"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Transmitted by food and water that have been contaminated.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Internal Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Transmitted from man to man through nasal droplet of an infected individual.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Respiratory|Respiratory Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "It is a sexually transmitted disease through sexual intercourse.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Venereal|Venereal Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Illness that can be transmitted from man to man or from animal to man.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Communicable|Communicable Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Transmitted from person to person by insect.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Insect Borne|Insect Borne Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Never stay in a crowded place where in you have identified a person with a disease.",
    "type": "fill-q",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "Field Sanitation"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The following are Venereal Disease that transmitted through sexual intercourse except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["AIDS", "Herpes", "Gonorrhea", "Malaria"],
    "answer": "Malaria"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The following are carrier of Communicable Disease except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Food and Water", "Air-borne Droplet", "Gonorrhea", "Sexual Contact"],
    "answer": "Gonorrhea"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The following are carriers of Intestinal Disease except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Yellow Fever", "Fingers", "Foods", "Feces"],
    "answer": "Yellow Fever"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Transmitted from man to man through nasal droplet of an infected individual.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Communicable Disease", "Internal Disease", "Foods", "Respiratory Disease"],
    "answer": "Respiratory Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Deals with these measures taken by the individual to preserve his own health.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Sanitation", "personal Hygiene", "Health", "Hygiene"],
    "answer": "personal Hygiene"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Transmitted from person to person by insect.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Insect Borne Disease", "Internal Disease", "Communicable Disease", "Respiratory Disease"],
    "answer": "Insect Borne Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Illness that can be transmitted from man to man or from animal to man.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Insect Borne Disease", "Internal Disease", "Respiratory Disease", "Communicable Disease"],
    "answer": "Communicable Disease"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The following are in Field Sanitation except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Don't sail the ground with urine and feces.", "Avoid intercourse with prostitute woman.", "Don't used a mosquito net and other sleeping paraphernalia.", "Avoid contact with animal wherein sanitation is poor."],
    "answer": "Don't used a mosquito net and other sleeping paraphernalia."
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The following are Personal Cleanliness and Care to maintain Good Health except in one.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Cut finger nails regularly", "Washed your hand before touching any food to eat.", "Never brush your teeth every after meals.", "Whenever possible get 7-8 hours' sleep each night."],
    "answer": "Never brush your teeth every after meals."
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "It is science that deals with health and its maintenance.",
    "type": "multi-q",
    "choices": ["Sanitation", "personal Hygiene", "Health", "Hygiene"],
    "answer": "Hygiene"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The five F carriers of intestinal Disease are Foods, Files, Fingers, Fluid, Feces.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Contagious and Infections are Communicable Disease.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Malaria and yellow Fever are Insect Borne Disease.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "AIDS, Syphilis, Herpes and Gonorrhea are Carriers of Communicable Disease.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Direct contact with the people, Food and Water, Sexual Contact and Insect and Animal Bites are Venereal Disease.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "The importance of Personal Hygiene It enlightened and protects the individual or group against the spread of diseases in the environment.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Diseases Acquired with Poor Hygiene and Sanitation.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Personal Cleanliness and Care to maintain Good Health is not Important.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "Internal Disease It is transmitted from man to man through nasal droplet of an infected individual.",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "FALSE"
  },
  {
    "topicid": 13,
    "question": "It is important to that we have a Hygiene and Sanitation",
    "type": "tof",
    "choices": null,
    "answer": "TRUE"
  }
]